# **Andrew Bridger**

(m) +44 7759 512091 andrewjohnbridger@gmail.com

#### **Professional Overview**

I am an Economist who is passionate about applying and communicating economic principles to create better outcomes for all. I have 5 years professional experience in economic policy and research. I am on a sabbatical from the Australian Industry Group, where I hold a Senior Economist role, to complete my Masters in Economics at the University of Edinburgh, Scotland.

### **Professional Experience**

Senior Economist (on sabbatical in the United Kingdom)
The Australian Industry Group (Ai Group)

Dec 2017 – Current Melbourne, Australia

Responsible for analysis and commentary on Australian and international economic developments.

#### Key responsibilities:

- Providing economic advice and research
- Presenting economic updates to Government agencies, journalists and business
- Preparing Ai Group business surveys and research reports
- Statistical analysis
- Policy analysis

# Graduate Department of Industry, Innovation and Science

Feb 2016 – Dec 2017 Canberra, Australia

Employed as part of the two-year graduate program. Worked across the budget process, industry growth sectors and modelling workforce requirements to deliver government services.

#### Key responsibilities as a Data Analyst include:

- Modelling workforce requirements and making recommendations based on the modelling to the Executive
- Budget analysis
- Working on whole-of-division projects

# Research Economist Synergies Economic Consulting

Jan 2015 – Jul 2015 Brisbane, Australia

Hired as a summer intern and upon completion of my internship, I was asked to stay on while finishing my university studies.

#### Key responsibilities:

- Economic research on wheat supply chains, port facilities and the energy market
- Policy updates
- Report writing

## **Early Career Summary**

Ipsos Research Computer Assisted Telephone Interviewer	2013 - 2015
Strut N Fret Festival Bar Team Bartender	2012 - 2014
Direct 2 Consumer (D2C) Brand Ambassador	2011 - 2012

#### **Qualifications**

Master of Science in Economics University of Edinburgh

2021 - Current Edinburgh, UK

Course component will be done by May 2022

# Bachelor of Commerce/Economics University of Queensland

2011-2015

Brisbane, Australia

- Majored in Finance (Commerce) and Quantitative Methods (Economics)
- Grade Point Average of 5.6 (out of 7)
- Exchange semesters at the University of Massachusetts and Kansas State University
- 2012 Dean's Commendation for High Achievement

### Graduate Certificate in Management (Public Sector) University of Canberra

2017

Canberra, Australia

• Grade Point Average of 6.0 (out of 7)

### Summary of Skills

- Data analysis to inform decision-making
- Excellent written communication skills
- Statistical software (R and EViews)
- Advanced excel skills

- Ability to present complex economics concepts to a lay audience
- Enthusiasm for responsibility
- Attention to detail

#### Referees

Julie Toth

The Australian Industry Group

Chief Economist

Contact details available on request

Lisa Hind

Department of Industry, Innovation and Science General Manager - State and Territory Network within AusIndustry Contact details available on request

Jeffrey Lassen

Managing Director at FTI Consulting Former Principal at Synergies Economic Consulting Contact details available on request